Emmanuel Chukwuma

6116 41st Ave, Hyattsville, MD 20782

• emmanuelc04@yahoo.com

• (240)-264-7589

Accomplished in both healthcare and technology sectors, with a proven track record at George Washington University Hospital. Experienced in patient assessment and IT fundamentals, I excel at triage and problem-solving in high-pressure environments, demonstrating exceptional multitasking and communication skills. My approach consistently enhances patient care and technology support outcomes, reflecting a commitment to excellence and efficiency.

Skills

- Patient Monitoring/Patient Assessment
- CPR/Basic Patient Life Support
- EKG Monitoring
- IV Catheter Insertion/Ultra-sounded IV
- Customer Service
- Triage/Multi-Tasking
- Interpersonal and communication skills
- Detail-oriented
- Microsoft 365
- Active Directory
- IT Fundamentals

Work Experience

World Wide Tech Services – Tewksbury, MA (Remote)

November 2023 – Current

Dynamic Tech Support

- Maintained and acquired knowledge of latest software and hardware to support needs of clients
- Effectively communicated technical issues and resolutions with clients
- Triaged incident tickets and technical issues and provided basic to moderately-complex troubleshooting and resolutions

Holy Cross Hospital - Germantown, MD

February 2022 – Current

Emergency Room Tech

- Inserted peripheral IV catheters and venipuncture blood draw in adult and pediatric patients
- Performed orthopedic immobilization, non-plaster splints, and slings
- Utilized computer skills to document procedures and record activities
- Performed and analyzed twelve lead EKGs

George Washington University Hospital – Washington, DCJuly 2019 – June 2023 PACU Recovery Unit

- Provided transportation of patients to and from surgical procedures
- Effectively communicated timely and complete information to patients
- Built sustainable relationships with family members and patients with professionalism

George Washington University Hospital – Washington, DC March 2016 – June 2023 *Emergency Room Technician*

- Started IVs and performed ultrasound-guided IV
- Utilized computer skills for documentation of procedures and records
- Exemplified the core values and beliefs of George Washington University Hospital in providing care for patients

Washington Adventist Hospital – Takoma Park, MD

February 2013 – July 2019

Emergency Room Technician

- Triaged emergency room response procedures including starting IVs, EKGs, splinting, and transporting
- Provided guidance to patients and family members through the emergency room process
- Provided exceptional patient care adhering the standards of Washington Adventist Hospital

Washington Adventist Hospital – Takoma Park, MD

Sept. 2011 – February 2013

Transporter

- Provided high-quality care and visitors and patients
- Operated vehicles and carefully followed all safety protocols and procedures
- Used effective communication in responding to requests and providing updates

Washington Adventist Hospital - Takoma Park, MD

June 2010 – Sept. 2011

Volunteer - Pharmacy Tech Assistant, Occupational Health File Manager

- Performed tasks and responsibilities in an effective and efficient manner as both a Pharmacy Tech Assistant and Occupational Health File Manager
- Provided effective support to staff to improve positive workflow
- Utilized problem-solving skills to serve patients and address hospital administration needs

Education

Stratford University – Alexandria, VA

June 2020 – October 2022

Nursing

Prince George's Community College – Largo, MD

September 2018 – May 2020

Pre-Nursing

Montgomery College – Takoma Park, MD

June 2020 – October 2022

General Studies

Accomplishments

- Washington Adventist: Over 1,000 Volunteer Hours recorded
- Washington Adventist: Five Years of Dedicated Service
- George Washington University Hospital: Employee of the Month
- George Washington University Hospital: Daisy Award